Guide to the Greater Yellowstone Coalition records1984-2020
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Greater Yellowstone Coalition Records
1984-2020
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Greater Yellowstone Coalition
2649
25 linear feet
Organization formed in response to a number of increasing threats to the Greater Yellowstone ecosystem in the western United States an area which spans 20 million acres and extends into three states (Idaho, Wyoming, and Montana). The collection contains records that track both the group's founding and the arc of its environmental campaigns over three decades, and largely comprises administrative, planning, and research documents. A large number of still photos, audio, and moving images are also part of the collection.
The Greater Yellowstone Coalition (GYC) was founded in May 1983 by a group of 35 conservation organizations in response to a number of increasing threats to the Greater Yellowstone ecosystem in the western United States an area which spans 20 million acres and extends into three states (Idaho, Wyoming, and Montana) as well as two national parks (Yellowstone and Grand Teton). The stability and health of this ecosystem was actively endangered by mining, drilling, geothermal development, logging, roads, subdivisions, and human overuse. The group felt that the area lacked a state/federal administrative structure that could properly respond to these threats, and sought to create an environmental advocacy group which could manage multi-state coordination efforts.
The area that the coalition focuses on encompasses two national parks and surrounding protected lands. Established in 1872, Yellowstone National Park was the country's first national park, set out over 3,500-sq area covering parts of Wyoming, Idaho and Montana. Prior to the formal establishment, humans had been living and traveling in the area for over 11,000 years. First, a variety of Native American tribes lived in and traveled through the park, and then in the early 1800s European Americans began to explore it. The area also includes the Grand Teton National park, which is located in Wyoming. First founded in 1929, the original park included a smaller area than today, just the Teton Range and surrounding lakes. Over the years, more land was set aside for the park, by Congress and a section purchased by John D. Rockefeller with the intention to donate. In 1950, the park in its current state of 480 sq miles was established with the combination of the original land, the Jackson Hole National Monument and the Rockefeller donation.
GYC's founding mission, established at the group's 1983 founding convention at the Teton Science School in Jackson, Wyoming, embraced protection of the Greater Yellowstone ecosystem in its natural condition. Convention attendees elected a thirteen-member steering committee, made up of members from Idaho, Wyoming, and Montana, comprising the first GYC Board of Directors. They adopted three primary goals: fostering citizen action through outreach efforts, developing both regional and national awareness around the Greater Yellowstone ecosystem, and promotion of the scientific concept of the ecosystem itself.
Robert L. Anderson was appointed GYC's first Executive Director in 1984, and the group debuted at the 1984 annual meeting, held at Yellowstone National Park's Mammoth Hot Springs Hotel. By then, the organization's primary office had been established in Bozeman, Montana, and infrastructure efforts began to transition into coalition-building and garnering member support. Both 1984 and 1985 saw the group's environmental advocacy efforts crystallize and gain traction, particularly around protection of the Yellowstone grizzly bear population, the reintroduction of wolves into the Greater Yellowstone ecosystem, advocacy for expanded wilderness designations, site-specific issues and protection, and support for state-level and Congressional wilderness bills.
In the nearly four decades that GYC has been in operation, it has served as the focal point for education, advocacy, and outreach around the preservation of the Greater Yellowstone ecosystem. One of the group's first projects centered on the development of the New World Mining District in the Gallatin National Forest, Park County, Montana. GYC was a leader in the fight to ensure that the northeast corner of the Greater Yellowstone ecosystem was kept from becoming a gold mine. In 2007, GYC was part of a group that sued to block the de-listing of grizzly bears from the U.S. list of endangered species. The group has been instrumental in the protection and preservation of several rivers in the ecosystem, including portions of the East Rosebud River, the Snake River, and the Yellowstone River. It has successfully pushed for legislation preventing mining and development in public lands and driven efforts to protect bison, wolves, native fish, and grizzly bears residing in the ecosystem.
The organization holds an annual convention each year, drawing academics, legislators, students, and advocates for several days of scientific education, recreational outings, brainstorming sessions, and policy-setting.
Notable Events:
1990s -- a leader in the fight against the development of the New World Mining District. Successful in blocking
2007 -- part of a group that sued to block the delisting of Grizzly Bears from the Endangered Species Act list
2015-2019 -- Yellowstone Gateway Protection Act; protects public land in the mountains East of Paradise Valley and North of Yellowstone National Park from mining claims
Caroline Byrd stepped down from her role as Executive Director on February 29, 2020, having served as ED since 2013. GYC Deputy Director Scott Christenson served as the Interim Executive Director before being named the new Executive Director in July 2020.
This collection serves as the administrative record of the Greater Yellowstone Coalition. While it does contain some administrative records, contents of the collection primarily consist of planning materials related to the organization's annual meeting, press clippings topically related to the group's environmental advocacy work, and some miscellaneous video recordings created by GYC for educational and promotional purposes. Topics in the collection include: the reintroduction of wolves to Yellowstone, protection of Grizzly bears, designating protected wilderness areas in the GYE against mining and other developments. It also includes a web archive.
The collection is divided into six series: 1. Administration, 2. Annual Meeting (with two subseries: 1. Planning Materials and 2. Video Recordings), 3. News Clippings, 4. Video Recordings, 5. Publications, and 6. Web Archive.
The collection is open for research.
Collection was in custody of Greater Yellowstone Coalition before being donated to MSU Special Collections.
Gift of Greater Yellowstone Coalition, 2019. Addition of web archive in 2020.
Greater Yellowstone Coalition
Yellowstone National Park; Montana
Conservation of natural resources--United States; Poaching; Conservation of natural resources--Montana; Natural resources conservation areas
National Parks; Environmental Activism; Montana
- Administrative, 1984-2018; 1; 2 boxes
  This series contains items pertaining to the administration of GYC, such as annual reports generated by the organization, mailings about projects, and press releases. It also contains congressional testimonies related to the issues worked on by the organization such as wildlife conservation.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - "Alerts" mailings, 1984-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Alerts" mailings, 1984-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual reports, 1985-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual reports, 1996-2003 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual reports, 2006-2015 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual reports, 2016-2018 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bison and the Fund for Animals, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bison and the Fund for Animals, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bison and the Fund for Animals, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Congressional testimonies, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Draft, Greater Yellowstone Coalition Program Plan, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - InfoSheets (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Maps (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - News Summaries, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets and mailings, 2001-2016 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets and mailings, 2001-2016 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets and mailings (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Press releases, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Press releases, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1993-2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Reports (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Status Report on Yellowstone Grizzly Bear, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sue-Ann Hanson staff files, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Annual Meeting, 1984-2018; 2; 9 boxes
  This series is focused on the annual meetings held by GYC, and is split into two sub-series. Subseries 1 contains the planning materials for the meetings, and sub-series 2 contains audio recordings of the meetings, mainly in the form of audio cassettes, along with some CDs and DVDs.
  Materials are organized chronologically.
  - Planning Materials, 1985-2011; 1; 3 boxes
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting transcripts, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Annual Meeting Materials, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Sound and Video Recordings, 1985-2013; 2; 9 boxes
    Recordings of the annual meetings, the majority of which are in the form of audio cassettes, though in 2001 they start to appear on CDs and DVDS. Some tapes are missing in some sequences and there are also no tapes for the years 1987-1988 and 1996. Each tape has information about the date and description of its contents on it written on the container, although the level of detail varies.
    - Annual Meeting recordings, June 7-8, 1985 (Box 6, Audiocassette 1-4)
      Tape #1-3: Scientific Conference-Defining a Healthy Greater Yellowstone Ecosystem Panel. Tape #4: Grizzly Bear Panel
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 1986 (Box 6, Audiocassette 5)
    - Annual Meeting records, 1989 (Box 6, Audiocassette 6-17)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 1989 (Box 7, Audiocassette 18-31)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, May 18-20, 1990 (Box 7, Vhs 1-2)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 1991 (Box 7, Audiocassette 33-48)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, May 29-30, 1992 (Box 8, Audiocassette 49-56)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, May 14-15, 1993 (Box 8, Audiocassette 57-66)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, May 14-15, 1993 (Box 9, Audiocassette 67-69)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, May 14-15, 1994 (Box 9, Audiocassette 70-84)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, May 14-15, 1994 (Box 10, Audiocassette 85-91)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, May 12-14, 1995 (Box 10, Audiocassette 92-102)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, May 12-14, 1995 (Box 11, Audiocassette 103-110)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, May 30-31, 1997 (Box 11, Audiocassette 111-121)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, June 5-6, 1998 (Box 11, Audiocassette 122-128)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 1999 (Box 11, Audiocassette 129-136)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 2000 (Box 11, Audiocassette 137-142)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 2001 (Box 12, Compact-disc 1-9, Audiocassette 143, Vhs 3-5)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 2002 (Box 13, Compact-disc 10-27, Audiocassette 144-146)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 2003 (Box 13, Compact-disc 28-29, Dvd 1)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 2004 (Box 13, Compact-disc 30-38)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, June 10-11, 2005 (Box 13, Compact-disc 39-47)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 2007 (Box 14, Dvd 2-5)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 2008 (Box 14, Compact-disc 48-54)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, September 24, 2010 (Box 14, Compact-disc 55-58)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, 2011 (Box 14, Dvd 6-9)
    - Annual Meeting recordings, September 21, 2013 (Box 14, Dvd 10)
    - Unidentified recordings (Box 14, Compact-disc 59, Audiocassette 147-166)
- News Clippings, 1984-2018; 3; 38 boxes
  Contains a large number of newspaper clippings about subjects the Coalition focused on and tracked, such as grizzly bear and wolves in Yellowstone Park, ranching, mining. It also contains clippings that mention the GYC.
  Materials are generally arranged by year, starting in the 1980s. There is also some alphabetical arrangement by subject, though this is not uniform throughout the entire series.
  - GYIBC (Greater Yellowstone Interagency Brucellosis Committee), 1996 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - GYIBC (Greater Yellowstone Interagency Brucellosis Committee), 1997 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - GYIBC (Greater Yellowstone Interagency Brucellosis Committee), 1997 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - GYIBC (Greater Yellowstone Interagency Brucellosis Committee), 1997 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition mentions, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Wilderness, 1984-1994 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Timber Subsidy, 1984-1994 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Timber, 1984-1994 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Park, 1984-1994 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Mining, 1984-1994 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Mining, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Mining, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Mining, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Mining, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Wolves, late '87, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Wolves, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Wolf, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Wolf Hearing, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Wolves, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Griz (Grizzly), 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Bear, 1984-1994 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Bear, '85-'87, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Bear, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Bear '87, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Griz (Grizzly) - NYRA (Northern Yellowstone Rim Alliance), 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Bear, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Bison, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Buffalo, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Bison, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Wise Use Movement, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - People FOF West, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Rancher Thinking, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Grazing, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Oil and Gas, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - AFWR (Alliance for the Wild Rockies), 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Wolves, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Geothermal, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Bison, 1984-1994 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Cut Geothermal, 1984-1994 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Geothermal, 1984-1994 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Winter Use, February 1986-June 2000 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Winter Use, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Winter Use, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Access, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Acid rain, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Air, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - ANWR, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Alston Chase, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - American Heritage Trust Fund, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Annual Meeting & Scientific Conference, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Appeals, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Association of Forest Service Employees for Environmental Ethics, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Bears within the Greater Yellowstone Ecosystem, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Bears outside of Greater Yellowstone Ecosystem, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Beaverhead National Forest, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Big Sky development, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Bighorn and domestic sheep, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Bison, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Bison, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Bison, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Bozeman development, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Birds, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Brand S, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Bridger-Teton National Forest, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Brooks Lake, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Bush Administration, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Cathedral Cliffs, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Cats, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Clark's Fork, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Clark's Fork, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Conservation groups, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Continental Divide Scenic Trail, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Controlled/Recreational burning, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Cottonwood Canyon, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Coyote (M-44 poisoning), 1990 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Cranes, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Dams, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Development regulation, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Eagles/falcons, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - East Boulder Mine, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - East Corridor Management Plan, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Ecology (national), 1990 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Economy, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Energy, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Elk, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Environmental laws, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Falls River, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Farming, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Ferrets, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Fires, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Fishing, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Gallatin National Forest, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Geysers/geothermal, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Global conservation, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Grand Teton National Park, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Grazing, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Greater Yellowstone Association of Conservation Districts, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coordination Commission, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Greater Yellowstone Tomorrow, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Greenhouse effect, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Greater Yellowstone Coalition supporters (general), 1990 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Greater Yellowstone Concepts and Coordination, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Hard rock mining and coal, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Hunting and outfitting, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Hyalite Canyon, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Interior Secretary, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Jackson Hole runway, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Jackson Hole development, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Land exchanges, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Land purchases, leases, and easements, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Law on public lands, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Medicine Bow National Forest and Sheep Mountain, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Medicine Wheel, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Mill/Emigrant timber sale, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Mining law (1872), 1990 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous plants and animals, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Moose, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Mount Ellis (including Harry Grant), 1990 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Multiple use, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Native Americans, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Noranda/New World/Cooke City gold mines, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Northwest News, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Nuclear waste (including INEL), 1990 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Oil and gas, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Oil and gas, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Our Land Society, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Owl Creek, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Pesticides, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Poaching, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Political Economy Research Center, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Politicians, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Pony Mill, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Plum Creek, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Private lands protection, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Public Lands Used Sensibly (PLUS), 1990 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Public land management, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Rivers, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Roads, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Shoshone National Forest, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Wolves, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Wolves, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Wolves, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Geysers/Geothermal, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Geothermal property rights, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Articles for you, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Access, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Acid Rain, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Air, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Alston Chase, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Appeals process--Feds, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Bears, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Beaverhead National Forest, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Bighorn Sheep, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Birds, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Bison, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Bozeman development, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Bridger-Teton National Forest, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Brooks Lake, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Coal, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Conservation groups, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Coyotes (M-44 poisoning), 1992 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Custer National Forest, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - CUT, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Dams, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Drought, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Development, general, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Eagles/falcons, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Economy, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Elk, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Endangered species, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Energy--general, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Environmental laws, 1992 (Box 25, Folder 14)